>> Jem Young: 有一个，哪个队 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: There is a,
which team is it?
我忘了他们在谷歌的电话
I forget what they're called at Google.
如果你问我我的梦想工作是什么，如果我是安全的，那就是谷歌 X 团队或者
If you ask me what my dream job is, if I
was in security, it's the Google X Team or
就像这样
something like that.
他们的工作只是黑进了
And their job is only to hack or
尝试在软件中找到零天，然后让制造商知道。
try to find zero days in software,
then they let the manufacturer know.
他们就像白帽黑客一样
And they do that as
being white hat hackers.
这就像在世界上做得很好，就是，
And it's kind of like doing
good in the world, which is,
这工作真的很酷
it's really cool that that job exists.
但其中一个问题是关于安全问题
But one of the issues is about,
when it comes to security,
如果我是一名安全研究员我说
is if I'm a security researcher and
I say, hey,
前端主控在软件中有一个安全漏洞。
Frontend Masters,
you have a security hole in your software.
我告诉你我有什么责任
And I tell you about that,
what responsibility do I have?
库兹本质上我找到了一个零日
Cuz essentially, I found a zero day.
我告诉你你什么都没做
And I tell you and
you don't do anything about that.
我该怎么办
What do I do?
What should I do?
我不认为我们今天要谈道德
I didn't think we were gonna
talk about ethics today.
但让我们谈谈道德问题。
But let's talk a little bit about ethics.
那么，公司的责任是什么 ?
So, what is the responsibility
of companies?
如果我说嘿，我在你的银行软件里发现了一个漏洞或者类似的东西。
If I say hey, I found a bug in your
bank software or something like that.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
这是个讨论你知道吗
Cuz this is a discussion, you know?
>> 演讲者 2: 补丁，他们应该修补缺陷。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Patch it,
they should patch the defect.
> > Jem Young: 但如果他们不呢 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: But what if they don't?
>> 扬声器 3: 设置时间和时间
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: A set amount of time and
然后你就会在推特上给他们施压
then you kind of put them on blast
on Twitter something to pressure.
> > Jem Young: 是的，现在我们进入了一个真正的灰色地带
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, and now we get
into a really ethically gray area, and
这就是为什么安全的原因我花了那么多时间在它上它真的很有趣
that's why security is, I spend so much
time on it cuz it's really interesting.
如果我说 Fronsend Masters 的 CEO 马克 - 格拉班斯基
Yeah, if I say, Marc Grabanski,
CEO of Frontend Masters,
我给你发邮件了 frontendmasters.com上有个漏洞
I emailed you that there's
a bug on frontendmasters.com.
我 30 天前给你发邮件你还没修好
And I emailed you 30 days ago and
you didn't fix it yet.
这就意味着如果我找到它别人就能找到它
And that means if I found it,
someone else can find it and
他们现在可以利用它我想你有责任解决这个问题
they can be exploiting it now and I think
it's your responsibility to fix that.
如果他们不这样的话我可以公开说
And if they don't,
at that point I can say publicly,
frontendmasters.com 有个漏洞我可以公开羞辱他们
hey, there's a bug on frontendmasters.com
and I can shame them publicly.
这在道德上是令人怀疑的
Which is ethically dubious,
在那个时候我把这个漏洞都给大家公布了
cuz at that point I just released
this vulnerability to everybody.
如果他们还没有解决这个问题，现在全世界都知道这个洞已经存在了。
And if they still don't fix it, now the
entire world knows that this hole exists.
这就是为什么安全研究人员是一个真正的人，它是一个非常棘手的领域。
And that's why security researcher is
a really, it's a really tricky area.
因为在什么意义上如果它是一个非常复杂的漏洞
Because at what point, like what
if it's a really complicated bug,
如果他们花了 30 天时间才能修好它呢
what if it takes them more
than 30 days to fix it?
我还是会释放它的
And I still release it anyways.
这对他们不公平，但也应该修复这个洞。
That's not fair to them, but
they should also fix the hole, too.
好的杰夫
Yes, Jeff.
>> 杰夫: 我想说的是，根据脆弱程度的复杂程度
&gt;&gt; Jeff: Well, I was gonna say, depending
on the complexity of the vulnerability and
有多少人可能受到影响
how many people are potentially affected.
据我所知有一套不同的标准
As I understand it,
there's a different set of standards for
您期望一家公司做出响应的紧急情况。
how urgently you expect
a company to respond.
还有就是你也可以在一段时间后宣布，
And the other thing is, you can also
announce after a certain amount of time,
无论是一个月还是六个月，你可以说，嘿，我们发现了一个漏洞。
whether it's a month or six months,
you can say, hey, we've found a bug.
你不必说它是什么地方，怎么利用它。
You don't have to say where it is or
how to exploit it.
6 个月或一年后就像这样
Versus six months or a year later,
it's like, by the way,
这就是我们发现漏洞的地方
this is where we found the bug.
还有一些 GitHub 存储库
And here's some available GitHub repos, so
任何孩子的剧本都能让它妥协
that any script kiddy could compromise it,
to show just how easy it is.
我的意思是，有一个渐进的反应，而不是仅仅是什么都没有。
I mean, there's a graduated response
rather than just all or nothing.
>> Jem Young: 是的，但即使在那里
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, but
even there it gets so
因为如果我说你的登录协议有漏洞的话
ethically dubious because what if I say
there's a bug with your login protocol.
我刚刚宣布，在世界上，他们还没有在 30 天， 90 天内解决这个问题。
And I just announce that to the world, cuz
they haven't fixed it in 30 days, 90 days.
足够让足够多的人开始酝酿
That's enough that enough people
are gonna start hammering on that and
他们可能也会发现这种脆弱性
they're probably gonna find
that vulnerability too.
所以即使你想做正确的事
So even then, even if you're
trying to do the right thing,
你还是会惹麻烦的
you can still get in trouble.
这个问题没有正确的答案。
There's no right answer to this.
谷歌的团队回应是他们向公司提供了 90 天的时间。
Google's team response is they
give 90 days to the company.
所以他们会告诉你如果你不在 90 天内解决
So they'll tell you about it and
if you don't fix it in 90 days,
他们会把它释放出来
they'll release that out into the world.
这就像是一种命名和羞辱的类型。
And it's kind of like a naming and
shaming type thing.
如果公司不作出回应
Which again,
if the company doesn't respond,
你刚刚把这个漏洞释放到世界上任何人都能利用
you've just released this bug out into the
world that anybody can take advantage of.
尤其是当你把这几天都链在一起
And especially when you start
chaining these zero days together,
你可以炸掉核反应堆之类的
you can blow up nuclear reactors,
things like that.
嗯。
Yes.
>演讲者 5: 最可怕的是我的医疗设备。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 5: The scariest one for
me is the medical device ones.
因为在 DEFCON 他们会做一件事
Because at DEFCON they'll do a thing,
a presentation,
你是怎么让这个起搏器杀了人的对吧
here's how you make this
pacemaker kill someone, right?
一些医疗设备公司不重视安全。
And some of the medical device companies
don't take security seriously.
所以我不知道这把我吓坏了
So I don't know,
that freaks me out anyways.
>> Jem Young: 它应该，你都应该被安全所吓到。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: It should,
you should all be freaked out by security.
当有小食的时候
And when there's hacks and
我们都应该集体追究这些公司的责任。
breaches, we should all collectively
hold these companies more accountable.
对不起，这完全是正切的，但因为我在乎这些事情。
Sorry, this is totally tangent, but
because I care about these sort of things.
Equifax ，他们有您的社会安全号码，所有信用记录，
Equifax, they have your Social Security
number, all of your credit history,
基本上我可以知道你是怎么花钱的
which essentially I can figure out who
you are by just how you spend your money.
他们被侵入了他们的后果对这些数据都是微不足道的
They got hacked and their consequences
were so minimal for this data that nobody
让他们收下，没有人让他们货币化，什么也没发生。
asked them to collect and nobody asked
them to monetize, and nothing happened.
所以说实话我觉得我们作为私人部门的工程师
So honestly, I think it's up to us as
engineers in the private sector to take
这些事情更严肃些，让公司承担责任。
these things more seriously and
hold companies accountable.
所以如果你看到你的公司有不良的安全惯例
So if you see your company
has bad security practice,
你应该说点什么
you should say something.
看什么说点什么吧
See something, say something.
[ LAUGH] 不管怎样，这是一个安全的切线。
[LAUGH] Anyways,
that was a tangent on security.
但到目前为止我们学到的东西就是让你的软件保持最新状态。
But what we've learned so
far is keep your software up to date.
这是你能做的最简单的事情之一
That's one of the easiest
things you can do,
在无人值守的升级过程中，它会为您提供服务。
with the unattended upgrades,
it does it for you.